《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
对了  我叫西斯科
I'm Cisco, by the way.
你就是吉普赛  很高兴认识你
You must be Gypsy. It's nice to meet you.
你是谁
Who are you?
爸爸
Daddy?
你是个战士  为了保护
You're a warrior who would fight to protect
我唯一爱的人而战斗
the only person I love.
我要使用解药
I want to take the cure.
我想要你在我离开后管理这个小队
You're the person that I want to run this team when I'm gone.
很抱歉对你动刀动枪了
Sorry I went all ice daggery on you.
但我仍然不喜欢你
I still don't like you.
拉姆齐  别这么做
Ramsey, don't do this.
只要我吸食能量  我就能永生
As long as I feed, I could live forever.
原来你一直藏在这里
So this is where you've been hiding.
有时候
Sometimes the truth
真相才是最难以看透的谎言
is the hardest lie to see through.
当你无法再相信真相的时候
And when you can't put your faith in the truth...
你只能靠自己
all you have left is yourself.
拉蒙  你被捕了
You're under arrest, Ramon.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第五集
12小时前
巴里  我们不需要这样做
Barry, we don't have to do this.
我们是去大溪地  又不是铁山监狱
It's Tahiti, not Iron Heights.
我知道  但是现在事情太多了
I know, but we've got too much going on right now
我们不该去度假
to be taking a vacation.
听着
Okay, look.
我们就去两天  好吗
It's two days. All right?
拉姆齐已经失踪两周了
Ramsey's been off the grid for two weeks.
危机即将来临
And Crisis is coming.
无论如何
No matter what.
让我带你去个特别的地方
Let me take you someplace special,
在那我们能喝上插着小伞的水果酒
where we can have fruity umbrella drinks
能在脚趾间踩满细沙
and get sand between our toes.
我确实喜欢二人世界
I do like us.
还有迈泰鸡尾酒喝就更好了
And we're even better with Mai Tais.
你看  一本书里有写
You gotta take a look. It's in a book.
我以为你俩已经去度假了
Hey, I thought you guys fathwoomed out of here.
我们只是想确保在我们离开的时候
We just wanted to make sure you guys were okay
你们能坚守阵地
holding down the fort while we were gone.
我们没问题  放心去度假吧小情侣
We're good. Rest easy, lovebirds.
队长已经成为我的新中间名
Team Leader is my new middle name.
以前是什么
What was it before?
巴拉克斯
Baracus.
阿根廷那个巴拉卡斯吗
As in Barracas, Argentina?
不  是T先生的那个巴拉克斯
No, as in Mr. T.
我妈是《天龙特工队》的超级粉丝
My mom was a big "A-Team" Fan.
要是我妈也是就好了
Wish mine was.
也许就会给我起名叫汉尼拔·德比了
Could've been Hannibal Dibny.
汉尼拔
Hannibal?
得了吧  你最多也就能配上默多克这个名字
Please. You're Murdock on your best day.
你们度假愉快
You guys have fun.
我会借助一位朋友的帮助
I'm gonna hold it down
来坚守阵地
with a little help from my friend,
那位巴里
the Barry.
那位巴里  我就在这呢
The Barry? I'm standing right here.
不是你  巴里
Not you, Barry.
是这个巴里智脑
B.A.R.I.
巴里·艾伦复制智能
Barry Allen Replicated Intelligence.
是我写的决策算法
It's my decision-making algorithm.
如果出现了问题
So if there's a problem,
这个会告诉我们该怎么做吗
this is gonna tell us what to do?
没错  它是基于巴里以往作为队长的决策
Yes, and since it's based on his past leadership choices,
对于任何情况
it'll tell me how to handle any situation
它将准确地告诉我他会怎么处理
exactly like he would.
受宠若惊
I mean, I'm flattered, I think.
巴里最喜欢我给他做什么早餐
What is Barry's favorite thing that I make him for breakfast?
香蕉
Banana?
巴里最喜欢爱瑞丝给他做什么早餐
香蕉
还有谁想试试
Who's next?
电脑  巴里最喜欢的电影是什么
Okay, computer, what's Barry's favorite movie?
《帝国反击战》
"Empire."
巴里最喜欢的电影是哪部
《侏罗纪公园》
还好不是
Oh, thank God.
这么一说
Actually...
我这辈子都非常爱
I mean, I've loved, loved "Empire Strikes Back"
非常爱《帝国反击战》这部电影
my whole life, but...
但是现在仔细想想
now that I think about it...
我的天
Oh, my God.
我最喜欢的电影确实是《侏罗纪公园》
My favorite movie is "Jurassic Park."
-没错吧  -它是怎么做到的
- There it is. - How does it do that?
模糊逻辑和人工智能直觉
Fuzzy logic, and AI intuition, my guy.
有了巴里智脑  就好像你一直都在
With the B.A.R.I. By my side, it'll be like you never left.
我想我们该出发了
I guess we should get going.
没错
Yes, we should.
给我寄明信片
Send me a post card.
记住  我是交给你负责了
Look, remember, I'm leaving you in charge.
度假回来见
I'll see you when you get back.
拜拜
Bye.
有什么指示吗  老大
So you got any marching orders, boss?
巴里智脑让我守在这里
The B.A.R.I. wants me to stay here
你和冰霜去拉姆齐的实验室盯梢
and you to go with Frost to stake out Ramsey's lab.
我就喜欢按计划行事
I love it when a plan comes together.
告诉你吧
Just so you know...
我故意让你跟着我来这的
I let you follow me here.
就随你那么想吧
I let you think that.
乔·韦斯特队长  中城警局
Captain Joe West. CCPD.
你下来这里干什么
What brings you down here?
有你这张脸的人通常都有所隐瞒
People with your face usually have something to hide.
当我孩子巴里告诉我出现了一个新的威尔斯
So when my son Barry told me that there was a new Wells,
我就开始注意你了
I started keeping tabs on you.
我不知道我和那个威尔斯有多少不同
I don't know how new a Wells I am, and second,
而你说的注意我  是指你从停在湖滨大道上
keeping tabs, that's what you mean by spying on me
那辆不起眼的轿车里监视我吗
from that nondescript sedan parked up on Lake Avenue?
观察力很强  那么你为什么
Well-observed. So why are you...
要在城市里挖洞
digging holes in the city?
完全不认识的陌生人
Well, perfect stranger...
我在这座城市地底下挖洞是因为
the reason I'm digging holes underneath the city is--
慢着
oh, wait...
你可能不会明白
you couldn't possibly understand.
-试试看  -不要
- Try me. - Nah.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你要休息会
You need some rest.
天天通宵研究巴里智脑
All those late nights working on the B.A.R.I.,
这周你几乎没怎么睡觉
you've barely slept this week.
今晚  我会睡得很熟的
Tonight, I'm gonna sleep like a child
因为我有巴里智脑
'cause I got the B.A.R.I.
我有白噪声
and I got my white noise
还有我的宝贝
and I got my boo.
晚安
Goodnight.
你还好吧
You okay?
不好  一点也不好
No, not really.
我差点对自己上演《理发师陶德》
I just almost went Sweeney Todd on myself.
我为什么会这么做
Why would I do that?
也许我在梦游
Maybe I was sleepwalking?
这是你的新习惯
Yeah, that's kind of your new thing.
昨晚你也吵醒我了
Yeah, you woke me up last night, too.
我听到前门关门声  然后你站在那里
I heard the front door shut, and you were standing there
手里拿着钥匙  鞋子也穿好了
with your keys in your hand and your shoes on.
我半睡半醒  所以我就把你带回床上
I was half-asleep, so I just put you back to bed.
你为什么没和我说
Okay, why didn't you say anything?
我没觉得是什么大事
Well, I didn't think it was a big deal.
我...  就像是一次性的  因为你太累了
I-- just like a one-off, 'cause you're so exhausted.
这事很重要
Well, it is a big deal,
现在已经不是一次性的了
and it's not a one-off anymore, is it?
已经两次了
That's twice now that's happened.
宝贝  别紧张
Babe, relax.
你今天刚刚启动了巴里智脑
Okay, you just launched the B.A.R.I. today.
你需要时间让你这迷人的大脑休息
You need time to rest that sexy brain of yours.
我的大脑就像充满智慧的瑞恩·高斯林
My brain is the Ryan Gosling of genius intellects.
好
Okay.
下次我再梦游请告诉我好吗
Will you please let me know next time that happens?
好
Yes.
把那些剪刀藏起里  别让我拿到
And hide those scissors from me.
-好  -晚安  宝贝
- Okay. - Goodnight, babe.
晚安
Goodnight.
我爱你  我...
I love y-- I look...
很期待明天和你一起度过
forward to spending time with you tomorrow.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
好了  宝贝  晚安
Yeah, okay, babe. Goodnight.
天哪
Oh, my God.
没事  我认识他
It's okay. I know him.
他是我前女友的爸爸
He's my ex's dad.
穿越者
Hey, Breacher...
好久没想杀我了
long time no try to kill me.
是什么风又把你吹到
What brings you to my bedroom...
我房间
again?
穿越者
Breacher?
乔希
Josh.
是辛西娅
It's Cynthia.
她死了
She's dead.
不敢相信她不在了
I can't believe she's gone.
我再也见不到她了
And I never get to see her again.
辛西娅当时正在追捕一名高级黑客
Cynthia was tracking a high-level hacker.
外号叫
Goes by the name of...
回声
Echo.
她之前提到过这个人
She mentioned him before.
从来没人查出
Nobody's ever been able to figure out
他的真实身份
who he really is, right?
我们认为辛西娅查到了
We think Cynthia did.
但他如何抢先她一步  我们就不知道了
How he got the jump on her, we don't know.
我没看过她打输给过任何人
I don't see her losing a fight to anyone.
她赢了
She won the fight.
但是死在这里
Dying here just...
触发了回收暂隔防护屏障网
triggered her Collector QT-net.
暂时隔离防护屏障吗
The quara-temporal containment barrier?
吉普赛曾经说过这些屏障
Gypsy once said these barriers
就像是地球外围的超大震动场
were like supersized vibe fields around the planet.
回收者打开屏障
The Collectors put them up
这样疑犯就不能打开缺口逃去另一个世界
so a suspect can't breach their way to another world.
只有回收机构能开启屏障
And only the Agency can lift it.
就是说杀她的凶手还在这里
Meaning her killer is still here.
我要替辛西娅的死报仇
I'm going to avenge Cynthia's death.
震波要帮我报仇
And Vibe is gonna help me do it.
西斯科已经不是震波了
Cisco isn't Vibe anymore.
他已经决定服下超能力者的解药
He decided to take the meta-human cure.
你不担心会出现缺口精神混乱吗
Weren't you worried about breach psychosis?
有时你抑制超能力时  就会出现这种情况
It happens sometimes when you suppress your powers.
这
It's...
这样真的不好
it's really gnarly.
怎么个不好法
How gnarly?
出现幻觉
Hallucinations,
莫名其妙地昏迷
weird blackouts...
口干舌燥
dry mouth.
我没有抑制我的超能力  它们已经没有了
My powers weren't suppressed. They're gone.
就算他没有超能力
Well, even without his meta-powers,
西斯科还是能帮你的
Cisco can still help you.
他是个天才
He's a genius.
换做是巴里会怎么做
What would Barry do?
巴里智脑要我们去犯罪现场
The B.A.R.I. wants us to go to the crime scene.
听我说  你不必回到那里
Listen, you don't have to go back there.
我去就行了
I'll go.
我和你一起去
I'll come with you.
卡米拉  也许会有危险
Kamilla, this could be dangerous.
我们要对付的是杀手
I mean, we're dealing with a killer here.
我不能要求你跟我一起去
I can't ask you come to with me.
你没要求
You didn't.
我自愿的
I volunteered.
我就知道你不会让我失望
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
好吧
Okay.
你可以随便挥舞你的手机
You can dance around with that thing all you want.
早在那面墙倒塌前  这里就已经是信号盲区
This place is a dead zone long before that wall came down.
最终可能会拨通的
Well, it might eventually go through.
最起码我在试着帮忙  你在做什么
At least I'm trying to help. What are you doing?
我在尝试逃离这里  这就是我在做的
I'm getting us out of here. That's what I'm doing.
愚蠢
Stupid.
我有小队可以帮我们离开这里
Well, I have a team that could help us get out of here.
怎么帮
How?
他们要怎么帮我们
How are they gonna help us?
没人知道我们在这底下
No one knows we're down here.
我是警局队长
I am a precinct captain.
我有几十个警察和一整个支援小组
I have dozens of cops and a whole support staff
一周24小时需要我
that depends on me 24/7.
如果我几个小时不出现
If I don't show up for a couple of hours,
他们会来找我
they're coming looking for me.
好吧
All right.
看来有人是过于自信了
Somebody's over-confident.
你知道你没有什么吗
You know what you don't have?
你没有手机信号
You don't have cell phone service.
你没有无线网
You don't have Wi-Fi.
你没有任何手段能告诉任何人...
You have no way of telling anyone--
-你做什么  -我们在这下边
- What are you doing? - That we're down here.
-对吗  -放下
- Right? - Put it away.
这是我们唯一的选择
This is our only option.
我会带我们逃出这里的
I'm gonna get us out of here.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
住手
Stop!
你是什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
你为什么不告诉我
Why did you not tell me
这个地球的振动频率
that this Earth vibrational frequency
在分子水平上被校准过
is calibrated at a molecular level?
你才应该是专家
You're supposed to be the expert.
再这么嘘我  我们可就有麻烦了
Shush me one more time. We gonna have a problem.
我们已经有了
We already do.
看起来那个火球吸走了这个...
It turns out that that fireball sapped 80...
这个空间里百分之87的氧气
87% of the oxygen in this chamber,
也就是说我们还剩42分钟可以呼吸
which means that you and I have 42 minutes left to breathe.
你知道说好的是
You know, the idea was you'd call me
你在他开始杀人前通知我
before he started killing people.
他不知道从哪里突然出现
He showed up out of nowhere.
拉特和波普斯想要逃跑
Rat and Pops tried to run for it.
他们没有跑太远
They didn't get far.
冰霜  那家伙可是非一般的瘆人
Frost, that guy is next-level creepy.
我可不想去找他
I wouldn't go looking for him.
聪明的举措
Smart move.
尤其是没有队友的情况下
Especially without a partner.
生意如何  蛇罐子
How's business, Snake-shack?
不算太好
Had better days.
你能让我们独处会吗
You mind giving us a minute?
得和冰霜谈一谈
Need to have a little chat with Frosty.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
在找你
Looking for you.
怎么不监控拉姆齐的实验室了
What happened to staking out Ramsey's lab?
诺瓦克给我发信息  他看到拉姆齐在这里
Norvock texted me. He said he saw Ramsey here.
冰霜  作为你的生活导师
Frost, as your life coach,
一个人对付拉姆齐
going after Ramsey alone
可能会让我失去工作
is probably gonna put me out of a job.
这不是开玩笑
This isn't a joke.
这是场战斗  我的战斗
This is a fight. My fight.
所以别插手
So stay out of it.
我们是一个队伍
We're a team.
你的战斗就是我的战斗
Your fights are my fights,
你为什么不放松一下
so why don't you just take a breath
相信你的朋友
and try trusting a friend?
我从一开始就知道不能信任这家伙
I knew from day one not to trust this guy.
但是我们信了
But we did.
现在有人被他杀了
And now people are dead.
我要修复这一切
So I've gotta fix this.
不久之前我也有这种感觉
It wasn't that long ago that I felt the same.
怪罪自己  不让任何人帮我
Blamed myself, never asked anyone for help,
你知道最后我怎么样了吗
and you know where it got me?
身陷酒精与自卑之中
Eyeball-deep in Gingold and self-pity.
所以请相信我  在你对周围人
So believe me when I say that life is better
有信心的时候  生活会更美好
if you have faith in the people around you.
怎么了
What?
我知道拉姆齐对谁有信心
I know who Ramsey has faith in.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你没听到我刚才说的话吗
Did you hear anything I just said?
你不能一个人去
You can't go alone.
我知道我在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
别担心  我不会一个人
And don't worry. I won't be alone.
听着  卡米拉
Listen, Kamilla...
有件事我一直想要告诉你
there's something I've been wanting to say to you.
我一直不知道怎么说
I've been trying to figure out how to say it,
但是  我不知道
but I don't know.
我想我应该就直接说出来
I think I should just come right out and say it.
-卡米拉  我... -我的天啊
- Kamilla, I- - Holy crap.
我还以为中城警局的犯罪现场就够隆重的了
I thought CCPD's crime scenes were serious.
是  地球19的回收者特工
Yep. Earth-19 Collector agents
把调查上升到了另一个高度
take investigations to a whole other level.
扎克·吉尔特工
Agent Zak Zeal.
卡米拉·黄  西斯科·拉蒙
Kamilla Hwang, Cisco Ramon.
我听说你们要来了
Yeah, I heard you'd be coming.
我还以为你会高一些
I thought you'd be taller.
你知道的  从吉普赛谈你的方式来猜的
You know, from the way Gypsy talked about you.
有意思
That's funny.
她从没有提起过你
She never mentioned you at all.
确保沃克在更新
Make sure Walker is updating
维度输出报告
the dimensional output report.
谢了  当你成为领导之后
Thanks. You gotta keep on them constantly
就得不断督促他们
when you're in charge.
穿越者明白的
Breacher understands.
他去哪里了
Where is he, anyway?
他已经看过了他需要看的
He already saw everything he needed to see.
我们是替代他来了
We're here in his place.
机构已经允许你们加入调查了
Well, the Agency authorized you to join this investigation,
所以我想我只能放行了
so I guess I'll just have to let you.
死亡时间确定了吗
Is there a time of death?
因为多维信号的速率
Due to multi-dimensional signal speed,
我们最接近的猜测是发生在
our best guess is that it happened some time
在凌晨两点半至四点半之间
between 2:30 and 4:30 A.M.
-推断得很好  -我知道
- That's a pretty good guess. - Yeah, I know.
而且我们发现了这个
And we found this.
301-H能量弹壳
301-H energy cartridge.
标准规格  没有指纹
Standard issue. No prints.
把它和西格马粒子残留物结合起来
Combine it with the Sigma Baryon residue
我们还发现  这看起来像是...
we also found, and it looks like--
回声用跨音速去分子器杀死了吉普赛吗
Echo killed Gypsy with a transonic-demolecularizer?
带我们看看
Show us.
马上
Now.
她的身体  衣服
Her body, clothes,
甚至她的联络装备都蒸发了
even her communicator were all vaporized.
我这种状态...
Me being like this...
我不想让你觉得我还是没放下辛西娅
I don't want you to think I'm still hung up over Cynthia,
或什么的
or something.
西斯科
Cisco.
你关心的人死去了
Someone you cared about died.
要是你不难过  我才担心呢
I'd be worried if you weren't sad.
所以刚才我们到达那里的时候...
So earlier, when we first got here...
你是有些话想说吗
you were gonna say something?
卡米拉...
Kamilla...
我们准备封锁这里了
We're locking down the area.
你不是吧
For the love of God.
你俩得离开了
You two need to leave.
雷蒙
Ramon.
我只想重申一次  我有多欣赏吉普赛
I just wanted to say again how much I truly admired Gypsy.
我有很多要紧事得去办了
I've got some big shoes to fill.
我们不是真的就要这么放弃了吧
We're not seriously just gonna give up, are we?
不  我们不会放弃
No, we're not.
你有注意到  他是唯一一个会从
Have you noticed he's the only one who benefits
辛西娅的死亡中获利的人吗
from Cynthia's death?
所以我们的计划是什么
So what's the plan?
巴里智脑建议两个办法
The B.A.R.I. suggests a dual course of action.
首先  我们利用卫星追踪到
First, we use the satellites to track
那种武器特有的记号
the weapon's unique signature.
-你能...  -马上去做
- Can you... - On it.
我有认真听你说话
I've been paying attention.
其次呢
Second?
我们要挑战不可能了
We're gonna have to do the impossible.
兄弟  做下  冷静些
Man, sit down. Relax.
我们或许还能活得久一点
We may live longer.
你有任何证据显示会有人
What evidence do you have that anyone,
会有任何人
literally anyone,
跑到底下来救我们吗
is coming down here to rescue us?
我没有
I don't have any.
没有吗
No?
但我有信心
But I do have faith.
那样的话  队长
Ha! Well, then, Captain,
至少你没有丧失幽默感
at least you haven't lost your sense of humor.
有些头晕  你没有吗
Got light-headed, didn't you?
没有
No.
你就如此自私地不相信任何人或事
You selfishly don't believe in anything or anybody.
我以前也这样
I used to be like that.
当时我的前妻离开了我和我的女儿...
When my ex-wife left me and my daughter...
我心碎了
I was broken.
伤心到我去了一个我几乎从没去过的地方
So much so that I went somewhere where I almost never go.
教堂
Church.
我没去那里祈祷或做什么
I didn't go there to pray or anything.
我去那里大骂上天
I went there to yell at the universe
骂上天毁了我的生活
for destroying my life.
接下来  我回到家
Next thing, I'm at home.
我太难过了  甚至都没法...
I'm so hurt that I can't even...
做晚餐给我...
cook dinner for my...
给我女儿吃
for my daughter.
门铃响了
Doorbell rings.
我打开门  感觉所有的邻居都来了
I open the door to what looked like my whole neighborhood
站在我家门口草坪上
standing on my lawn
拿着给我们做的食物
who had cooked food for us.
你可以相信任何事  但是...
You can have faith in anything, but...
正是那个时候  我意识到
it was then I realized that I...
我可以相信人
I have faith in people.
根据巴里智脑
According to B.A.R.I.,
我们可以用低频率的德尔塔波震动
we can use low-level delta wave vibrations
德尔塔波  活动较缓慢的脑波
在我的前额皮质内引起谐波共振
to stimulate harmonic resonance in my prefrontal cortex.
如果我有任何同辛西娅的回忆
If I think of memories with Cynthia,
我们就能从杀死她的物体上
we'll be absorb the residual vibe energy
吸收残留的震波能量
from the object that killed her.
这个机器能恢复我的震波力量吗
Can this machine restore my vibe powers?
不可以  我们不是产生震波
No, we're not the generators of the vibe,
但我们会是类似感受器的存在
but we will be the receptors of it.
但我会看到辛西娅死去的画面  对吗
But I'm gonna have to see Cynthia die, won't I?
要找出凶手  这是我们唯一的办法了
It's the only way we have of finding out who killed her.
我的白噪音机器
My white noise machine
会产生德尔塔波波型
will stimulate our delta-wave patterns.
加入弹壳来触发整个过程
Add the shell casing as a trigger,
然后就可以了
and that'll do it.
巴里智脑  启动人工振动序列
B.A.R.I., initiate artificial vibrational sequence.
如果我们想要成功
If we want this to work,
我们得有身体接触
we have to make physical contact.
跨音速去分子器
已定位
你杀死了我女儿
You murdered my daughter.
不是
No.
不  我没有
No, I didn't do it.
我发誓
I swear.
-骗子  -你得相信我
- Liar! - You have to believe me!
放开他
Leave him alone!
你从哪找到这个的
Where did you get that?
在西斯科的工作室  我也不知道怎么跑那去的
In Cisco's workshop. I don't know how it got there.
我知道
I do.
他用这个杀死了我的女儿
He just murdered my daughter with it.
不  穿越者
No. Breacher.
我不管你觉得自己看到了什么  好吗
I don't care what you think you saw, okay?
你了解西斯科
You know Cisco.
你知道他有多在乎吉普赛
You know how much he cared about Gypsy.
这事肯定有其他解释的
There's gotta be another explanation.
宝贝  别说了
Babe, please.
万一他是二重身呢
What about doppelgangers?
没错
She's right.
外面还有成千上万个我
There's thousands of other versions of me out there.
他们都是白领混混
Yeah, and they're all pencil-pushers.
只有你一个是科学家
None of them are scientists like you!
你有动机
You had motive,
还有足够的胆识做出这事
and just enough guts to do this.
穿越者  我发誓
Breacher, I swear.
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know how this is possible.
除非
Unless...
除非是缺口精神错乱
Unless breach psychosis.
卡米拉  你是什么时候看见我梦游的
Kamilla, what time did you find me sleepwalking the other night?
记不清了  凌晨四点左右
I don't know. Maybe 4:00 a.M.
就是你干的
You're guilty.
但你当时神志不清
But you're not in your right mind.
我不仅在今天失去了女儿
I didn't just lose a daughter today.
我还失去了一个儿子
I lost a son.
因为
Because...
我敬你曾是个好汉
I still respect the man you were.
现在  给你一个小时的时间
Now I'm gonna give you an hour
让一切恢复正常
to get all your affairs in order,
然后自己去自首
and then turn yourself in.
不然我就亲自动手
Or I will end you.
你在做什么
what are you doing?
我要把这些石头炸上天
I'm gonna blow this blockade sky high.
把这里炸塌了  我们就死定了
You do that, this whole thing collapses, we're dead.
坐以待毙也是死路一条
I do nothing, and we're dead anyway.
我们可以等队友的营救
We still have time for my team to show up.
够了  别再扯你和你团队的破事了
Enough. Enough about your team and you.
你知道我站谁那边
You know where I stand.
你为何如此相信你的团队
How can you have such faith?
是因为有这么个人或是怪物自称监视者
Because someone or something called the Monitor
说我的儿子一定会葬身于某种危机之中
says my son is destined to die in some kind of Crisis,
唯一能让我稍感慰籍的
and the only way I can stomach any of that
只有坚信他暂未逝去的生命
is have faith that his continuing life
亦或他的死亡都是为了更...
or his death is for the greater...
为了更...
the greater...
为了成就更伟大的事
the greater good.
你见过监视者了
You've seen Mar Novu?
队长
Captain.
我来救你了伙计  你没事吧
I got you, big guy. You're all right.
你收到了我的讯息
you got my text.
没有
No.
我给中城警局报告拉姆齐的新行踪
I called CCPD with a Ramsey update,
发现没有人知道你在哪里
and nobody had seen you.
调查了一下  追踪你的车到这里
Ran your plates, tracked your car to a block from here.
你的笔记标记了这条隧道
Your notes had this tunnel marked.
我猜
I'm guessing...
都是因为他
because of him.
独行侠
Lone Ranger.
你好
Hi.
希波克拉底誓言
医生保证遵守医生职业道德的誓言
看来你收到了我留的讯息
I see you got my message.
凯特
Cait.
看到你这个样子还真有点奇怪
You know, it's a bit weird seeing you like this.
我想  我们都在不断改变着自己
I guess both our looks are evolving.
对  我收到了你的讯息
Yes, I did get your message.
让我想起了曾经和你一同为你妈妈工作的时光
It reminded me of when we both used to work for your mom.
当时我还只是个小实习生的时候
Way back when I was a resident.
你那时就像是妈妈未曾拥有的女儿一样
You were like the daughter Mum never had.
你知道我刚开始还有点嫉妒吗
Do you know at first I was jealous?
久而久之  我才减少了对你的敌意
Over time, I came to see you less as a rival
把你当姐姐看待
and more like a sister.
因此我给你一个加入我的机会
And that's why I'm offering you a chance to join me.
你想把我也给杀了
You want to kill me, too.
我在提供永生的机会  凯特
I'm offering you life, Cait.
我已经能掌控这能力  发现其中隐藏的美
I've learned to control it, discovered its secret beauty.
这将是我最后的杰作  凯特
This my final masterpiece, Cait.
永生
Life eternal.
永垂不朽
Immortality?
你看
You see?
我不是个怪物
I'm no monster.
我是个奇迹
I'm a miracle.
你想要违逆自然法则
You're talking about reversing nature.
大自然没有给我们翅膀
Nature never meant for us to fly,
而我们却触碰到了星星
and yet we've touched the stars,
正因我们挣脱了大自然的桎梏
and not by being slaves to the shackles of the natural order,
超越了自然法则
but by transcending them.
看看你自己的一生  凯特
Take a look at your own life, Cait.
多少次不得不惜别友人
How many times have you had to say good-bye to people?
还有多少事情没有机会去完成
How many more have you not even had the chance to do so?
我的妈妈本应活着站在这里
My mum should be here.
你的爸爸本应活着站在这里
Your father should be here.
你的丈夫本应活着站在这里
Your husband should be here.
加入我
Join me,
永远不用再失去任何人
and this is the end of good-byes.
你将永远不会失去挚爱之人
No one you love will ever die again.
我已经见识过你那种生活了
I've seen your version of life.
简直就是噩梦
It's a nightmare,
但你还能做回你妈妈的好儿子
but you can still be your mother's son.
她对你相当的有信心  我也是
She had so much faith in you, and so do I.
你只需要相信你自己
You just need to have faith in yourself.
你说的都是疯言疯语
Your words are madness.
下次就由不得你选择了
Next time won't be a choice.
我们必须面对事实
Look, we have to face the facts.
我必须接受自己犯下的罪行
And I have to own up to whatever it is that I did.
你打算自首吗
You're gonna turn yourself in?
只能这样  我已经没法再相信自己了
I have to. I can't trust myself anymore.
没法再
Anymore?
自从巴里让你来当组长
You stopped trusting yourself
你就一直不相信自己
the moment Barry asked you to take over as team leader.
你做了个这么精密的装置
I mean, you built this elaborate device
就只是为了不用亲自做决定
just so you wouldn't have to make any decisions for yourself.
你这...
That's...
这件事我来帮你做决定
Let me make this decision for you.
你是无辜的
You are innocent.
你怎么这么肯定
How can you be so sure?
因为我相信你
Because I have faith in you.
问题是  你为什么不相信你自己
The real question is why don't you have any faith in yourself?
因为巴里要死了
Because Barry's gonna die.
如果我不能像他一样保护大家怎么办
What if I can't keep people safe the way he does?
我不是闪电侠
I'm not the Flash.
亲爱的
Babe.
巴里不是选择你成为闪电侠
Barry didn't choose you to be the Flash.
他要你做你自己
He chose you to be you.
这些质疑都不是你
All these doubts, they aren't you.
只是你脑中的噪音
They're just noise in your head.
它一直处于无线模式
It's been in Wi-Fi mode this whole time.
编码记录
这是什么
What is it?
这个代码
This code.
它把我的白噪音器
It's turned my white noise machine
变成了微型神经脉冲干扰器
into a micro neural impulse disruptor
就像在我脑电波里放了一个"无敌破坏王"
that could go all "Wreck-It-Ralph" on my brainwaves.
这种状况看起来像是缺口精神错乱
It might even look like breach psychosis.
谁会聪明到写出这种代码
Who'd be smart enough to code like that?
我
Me.
有时真相才是最难以看透的谎言
Sometimes the truth is the hardest lie to see through.
当你无法再相信真相的时候
When you can't put your faith in the truth...
你只能靠自己
all you have left is yourself.
拉蒙  你被捕了
You're under arrest, Ramon.
我投降
I surrender.
我有罪
I'm guilty.
嫌犯已被羁押
Suspect is in custody.
启动暂时隔离防护网移除程序
Initiate QT-net removal
将犯人转移至地球19
so the prisoner can be transferred to Earth-19.
收到
Copy that.
穿越者
Breacher.
那个分手魔方会告诉你需要知道的
That holo-cube will tell you everything you need to know
所有关于辛西娅的事
about what happened to Cynthia.
暂时隔离防护网已关闭
QT-net is off.
暂时隔离防护网已关闭  长官
QT-net's down, sir.
我来把他铐住
I'll cuff him.
抱歉我不得不这样做
Sorry it had to go down this way...
但我需要你解除防护网
but I needed you to lift the net.
重新启动暂时隔离防护网
Re-engage the QT-net.
需要四分钟
That'll take four minutes.
我不管是否需要四分钟
I don't care if it'll take four minutes.
快启动
Just get on with it!
我恨力场
I hate force fields.
-我知道  -西斯科
- I know. - Cisco.
你觉得我会让
You think I'm gonna let the man
杀害我女儿的人逃跑吗
that murdered my daughter escape?
不  长官
No, sir.
我也不会
And neither am I.
我到了
I'm here.
没有他的踪迹
There's no sign of him.
他的缺口传送门能量显示他在仓库东面
His breach portal energy puts him at the east end of the warehouse.
游戏结束了  回声
Game over, Echo.
不  你找到我了
Oh, no. You found me.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我骗回收者解除了暂时隔离防护网
I tricked the Collectors into lifting the QT-net.
我知道你会趁机逃走
When they did, I knew you'd jump at the chance
离开这里并试图打开缺口
to get out of here and try to open a breach.
我只需要追踪传送门能量
I just had to track the portal energy.
亲爱的  把他带回来
Babe, just get him back here
好让特工抓住他
so the agents can take him down.
在我离开的传送门启动之前
You have approximately two minutes
你还有大约两分钟
before my ride out of here boots up.
我和你说再见
I go bye-bye,
你去地球19的回收者监狱替我坐牢
and you take my place in Earth-19 Collector jail,
但是枪在你那里
but you're the one with the gun.
所以
So...
你会用它阻止我吗
do you have it in you to stop me?
我们会知道的  不是吗
I guess we'll find out, won't we?
你和别人不一样
You are an anomaly.
我真好奇为什么这么简单就能陷害你
Makes me wonder why it was so easy to frame you.
你不想知道我是怎样做到的吗
Don't you want to know how I did it?
也许你能学到点东西
You might learn something.
不用  我差不多已经猜到了
No, I pretty much figured it all out.
你到这里之后  杀死了回收者的顶级特工
After you got here, you killed the top agent in the Collective,
但是你还需要脱身的方法
but you still needed a way out.
于是你利用你的脸进入尖端科研实验室
So you used your face to get into S.T.A.R. Labs
将这把枪放在我的工作室
and plant this gun in my workshop.
是这样吗
Is that right?
目前没错
So far, so good.
但是黑进我的白噪音器
But hacking my white noise machine
让我梦游
to make me sleepwalk...
你就是在这里露出了马脚
That's when you tipped your hand.
不论在哪里  我都能认出那段代码
I'd recognize that coding anywhere.
鉴于我没有黑进去
And since I didn't hack it,
我知道一定是其他版本的我
I knew it had to be some other version of me.
我不仅是另一个版本的你
I'm not just some other version of you.
我擅长黑进多元宇宙数据库
I specialize in hacking multiversal databases
创造新身份
to create new identities.
我可以在一瞬间
I could change your world...
改变你的世界
in an instant.
你看  其它地方可能存在一个
You see, somewhere out there is a Cisco Ramon
不像你这么幸运的西斯科·拉蒙
who isn't as lucky as you are,
他没有你这样的工作
who doesn't have the job,
头脑以及生活
the mind, the life you have.
但是只要出价合理
But if the price is right,
回声就可以逆转命运
Echo can reverse those fortunes.
你可能明天早上醒来
And you might just wake up tomorrow
就过上别人的人生
living someone else's life.
这就是你为什么杀了她吗
Is that why you killed her,
这样你就可以继续向别人兜售这些假身份
so you could keep peddling these fake identities to people?
我没有杀吉普赛
I didn't kill Gypsy.
是你
You did.
要我说
I'll give her this.
她是个很难对付的斗士
She was a formidable fighter.
就算是这里最聪明的人也无法
But not even the smartest guy in the room could beat her
在近身格斗中赢过她  但这不重要
in hand-to-hand combat, but it didn't matter.
尽管她追踪了我好几年
Even though she'd been chasing me for years,
却一直不知道我的长相
she never even knew what I looked like.
所以她抓住我的时候  看到了我的脸
So when she caught me, and she saw my face,
只需要一瞬间  就是她迟疑的那一瞬
all it took was one moment, one moment of her flinching,
给了我用那把枪的机会
and that gave me the second I needed to use that gun,
就是现在你手里那把枪
the same gun that's in your hands right now.
需要我解释给你听吗  天才
Do you need me to spell it out for you, genius?
吉普赛的死是因为她看到我时
Gypsy is dead because when she saw me,
觉得自己看到了你
she saw you.
住嘴
Stop talking.
她根本没必要死  但她也不能放走我
She didn't have to die. She couldn't let me go.
她让我进入了这个地球  然后我把她蒸发了
She breached me to this Earth and I vaporized her.
不
No.
是的
Yes.
别难过  西斯科
Don't feel bad, Cisco.
你只是没我这样的水平
You're just not wired like me.
你说得对
You're right.
我比你要聪明得多
I'm a hell of a lot smarter.
我给那个武器编过程  只要有人用它射击
I programmed that weapon to trigger an anti-vibrational force field
都会触发反振动力场
around whoever fires it.
这次
In this case...
是你  天才
that's you, genius.
你收到我的分手魔方消息了吗
Did you get my holo-cube message?
你还真够慢的
Took you long enough.
回声在地球十九的牢房里
Echo is in an Earth-19 cell.
那是属于他的地方
Where he belongs.
对不起我对你失去了信心  西斯斯
I'm sorry I lost faith in you, Cisky.
你知道吗
You know what?
没事
It's okay.
情况一度看起来很糟糕
Things were looking pretty bad there for a second.
但我不明白的是  如果她要死了
But what I don't get, if she was dying,
为什么要到这里来
why come here?
因为她知道
Because she knew
你会将回声绳之以法
you would bring Echo to justice.
她必须把他引诱到这里  到这个地球
She had to lure him here, to this Earth.
她从没失去过对你的信心  西斯科
She never lost faith in you, Cisco.
现在这件事结束了
Now that this is over with,
我该怎么办
what am I gonna do?
和我要做的一样
Same thing I have to do.
开始治愈心伤
We start healing.
我想请你去参加
I want to invite you to...
辛西娅的追悼会
Cynthia's remembrance ceremony
去地球19
on Earth-19.
还有你
You, too.
不胜荣幸
I'd be honored.
辛西娅会喜欢你的
Cynthia would've liked you.
我也喜欢你
I do, too.
有什么理由不喜欢呢
What's not to love?
尴尬
Awkward.
我必须得走了
I have to go now.
好吧  对了
Well, uh, yeah.
我...
I, um...
我们还没说那句话
Well, we haven't...said it.
对  我明白
Yeah, I know.
所以  是的  我...
So...yeah, I, um...
我也是  棒极了
Me too. Big-time.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
请告诉我你回过家了
Please tell me you went home at some point.
我就知道我闻到了高倍防晒霜的味道
I knew I smelled SPF 90.
-玩得开心吗  -很开心
- How was it? - Amazing.
一天之内去了十五个海滩
15 beaches in 24 hours,
嫁给极速者的特权之一
one of the many perks of marrying a speedster.
切斯特的能量水平已经到87%了
Yo, Chester's energy level's already up to 87%?
状态更新
切斯特·P·朗克
对  没错
Yeah, yeah. The, uh--
精神增强室对他的治疗就快结束了
the M.A.C.'s gonna be done cooking him up any day now.
所以这个巴里智脑
So the B.A.R.I.
还挺成功的
was a success?
实际上  我必须摆脱它
Uh, actually, I had to get rid of it.
我是用了  试着用过了
I did use it-- try to use it--
只是在开始  不过...
at first, but...
过了一段时间  我最终意识到
over time, ‭I finally realized...
你已经知道会发生什么事了
And you already knew that was gonna happen.
这更充分的证明了你是领导团队的最佳人选
It's just more proof that you're the right person to lead the team.
西斯科  我们收到你的消息了
Cisco, we got your message.
我真的为吉普赛的事感到很难过
I'm--I'm really sorry to hear about Gypsy.
有些事你永远无法释怀
Some things you never get over.
但她的葬礼就在下周举行
But her service is next week.
你想让我们陪你一起去吗
You want us to come with you?
对  我是说  我们也爱她
Yeah. I mean, we loved her, too.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡米拉会陪我一起去  所以...
Uh, Kamilla's coming with me, so...
我非常幸运能拥有她
I'm very lucky to have her.
我这样有问题吗
Is it wrong to feel that way...
我是说  这一切才刚刚发生
I mean, with everything that just happened?
我就已经放下了
It's like I'm moving on,
什么样的人才会这样做
What kind of person does that?
深爱的人才会这样
Someone who is very much in love.
真有意思
It's funny.
我最终没有跟辛西娅在一起
Cynthia wasn't the person I ended up with,
但是
but, um,
我觉得她教会了我当遇到合适的人时
I think she taught me how to be the person I needed to be
如何成为自己想要的样子
for when the right person came along,
因为这个
and for that,
我永远不会忘记她
I will never forget her.
你的生命体征没问题  乔
Your vitals are good, Joe.
刚才忙着帮你们擦屁股
You know, in all the hubbub of saving your keister,
我还没机会问你们到底在那下面干什么
I never got to ask what the hell you were doing down there.
四十年代  没人会说"屁股"
In 1940s, no one says "Keisters."
纳什  如果你愿意告诉我们
Nash, if you would just tell us
你在那下面找什么
what you're looking for down there,
我们也许能帮你
we might be able to help you.
好吧  明天上午九点  隧道里见
All right, tomorrow morning, 9:00, tunnels.
把你的整个优秀团队都带来
Bring your whole fancy team.
我们为什么要这样做
Why should we do that?
因为...
'Cause...
我知道如何拯救巴里·艾伦
I know how to save Barry Allen.